[{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"8. After being ordered to attack a much larger army near Wihwa (“WEE-hwah”) Island, a general from this region instead returned to its capital and toppled King U (“ooh”). That man, Taejo (“TEH-jo”), established a dynasty whose later rulers included the developer of this region’s Hangul alphabet, Sejong (“SAY-jong”) the Great. With the help of the Ming dynasty and Admiral Yi’s turtle ships, forces from this region defeated two Japanese invasions to preserve its Joseon (“CHO-sun”) dynasty. For 10 points, name this East Asian region whose historic capitals include Kaesong (“KEH-sung”) and Seoul. ","answer":"ANSWER: Korea [accept Korean peninsula; accept Joseon until read] <World History> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"2. A book on this time period states that “all art constantly aspires to the condition of music.” Another book on this time period opens by considering “The State as a Work of Art.” Walter Pater and Jakob Burckhardt wrote their magnum opuses on this period, whose so-called “manifesto” was an unpublished Oration on the Dignity of Man. The common name for this period was coined in a book of biographies by Giorgio Vasari. In this period, the trivium was replaced by the Studia Humanitas, or humanities, due to the rise of humanism. For 10 points, name this period following the Middle Ages named for “rebirthing” classical wisdom. ","answer":"ANSWER: the Renaissance [or Rinascimento; or rinascita] <Philosophy> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"3. Six of these beings sit around a radio during a scene in which one of them named Antarctica claims that he will rejoice to see the Chernobyl disaster. A nurse named Belize visits a character who tells him about hearing the voice of one of these beings. In a work titled for these beings, Ethel Rosenberg haunts a man who pretends to have liver cancer. A play with two parts named “Millennium Approaches” and “Perestroika” is titled for these beings. These creatures title a play where Louis Ironson abandons Prior Walter, who suffers from AIDS. For 10 points, name these heavenly beings that are In America in the title of a play by Tony Kushner. ","answer":"ANSWER: angels [accept Angels in America] <American Literature> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"4. This leader called avant-garde art “dog shit” and told artists “Gentlemen, we are waging war on you” in the Manège (“ma-NEZH”) Affair. This leader made a rival the ambassador to Mongolia after defeating the Anti-Party Group. This man declared “We build for our children and grandchildren” while arguing with an American vice president in the Kitchen Debate. This leader told a group of western diplomats “We will bury you” days after sending tanks to crush the 1956 Hungarian Revolution. This leader took power after the death of a man whose “cult of personality” he denounced in his “Secret Speech.” For 10 points, name this man who succeeded Joseph Stalin as leader of the Soviet Union. ","answer":"ANSWER: Nikita Khrushchev (“KROOSH-choff”) <European History> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"5. A series of loops at the top of one copy of this musical work have been interpreted as tuning instructions. Hans von Bülow termed this work the “Old Testament” for the instruments that may play it. The first piece in this set, which is characterized by a series of simple C major arpeggios, accompanies the vocal melody of the Ave Maria setting by Charles Gounod (“goo-NOH”). Though Chopin’s set goes around a circle of fifths, his collection of preludes were likely inspired by the structure of this earlier work. This collection advances a system intended to allow one to play in any key. For 10 points, name this keyboard collection of 24 preludes and fugues in every major and minor key, by J. S. Bach. ","answer":"ANSWER: The Well-Tempered Clavier [or Das Wohltemperierte Klavier; or Das Wohltemperirte Clavier; or BWV 846–893; prompt on WTC; prompt on J. S. Bach’s preludes and fugues] <Classical Music> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"6. Defects of a protein in this organelle can cause the inability of a farnesyl group to be removed; that condition occurs in patients with Hutchinson–Gilford progeria. MCM2-7 is recruited to this organelle to participate in a process that is aided by BER (“B-E-R”) and NER (“N-E-R”). That process in this organelle is facilitated by PCNA and SSB’s. RAN protein facilitates transport through this organelle’s “pore complexes.” During prophase, the membrane of this organelle degrades as microtubules migrate to polar ends of the cell. Chromosomes condense in this double-membraned organelle during mitosis. For 10 points, name this organelle where DNA replication occurs. ","answer":"ANSWER: cell nucleus <Biology> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"8. This country’s president was asked about the server Crowdstrike in a 2019 press release, which encouraged that man to investigate this country’s Burisma energy company. The star of this country’s comedy TV show Servant of the People became its president in March 2019, defeating incumbent Petro Poroshenko. For 10 points, name this country whose President Volodymyr (“wo-lo-DIM-eer”) Zelensky was asked to investigate Hunter Biden by Donald Trump, sparking the latter’s impeachment process. ","answer":"ANSWER: Ukraine [or Ukrayina] <CE/Geo/Other/Pop Culture> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"8. In this novel, a false princess tries to get a man to marry her by tossing an embroidered ball into his hat. A kingdom of entirely women in this novel bear children by drinking water from a river. Characters in this novel include a man who is beaten 800 times after he shatters a crystal goblet and another controlled by a headband that tightens at will. A character born from a stone egg is trapped under a mountain for five hundred years in this novel, but is freed so that he, Zhu Bajie (“joo ba-j’yeh”), and Sha Wujing can assist a monk trying to obtain Buddhist scriptures. For 10 points, name this classical Chinese novel about Tang Sanzang’s quest to reach India with Sun Wukong. ","answer":"ANSWER: Journey to the West [or Xī Yóu Jì (“shee yo jee”); prompt on Monkey] <World/Other Literature> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"9. One form of ritualized worship in this faith may involve the dipping of bells into boiling water, which are then shaken over the observers. The name of a common religious structure built by members of this faith translates as “bird perch,” possibly related to nearby animistic traditions. Small wooden plates with wishes on them are hung at temples of this faith, which are often protected by thick braided ropes and zig-zag paper streamers. The Sacred Mirror is held in one complex devoted to this faith whose buildings are torn down and rebuilt every 20 years. In this faith, large gates known as torii symbolize the entrances to the world of kami. For 10 points, name this faith, the indigenous religion of Japan. ","answer":"ANSWER: Shintoism [accept kami-no-michi] (The unmentioned clues refer to kagura, ema, shimenawa, shide, and the Ise Grand Shrine.) <Religion> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"0. At equilibrium, that equation named for him can be derived from the Butler–Volmer equation by setting a quantity denoted “eta” to zero. This scientist’s “heat theorem” was the first statement of the third law of thermodynamics. In an equation named for him, RT over the Faraday constant times z is multiplied by the natural log of the reaction quotient. For 10 points, what German scientist names an equation for calculating reduction potentials of galvanic cells? ","answer":"ANSWER: Walther Nernst [or Walther Hermann Nernst] <Chemistry> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"1. The Knights Templar reportedly used a cipher based on the Maltese Cross to develop an early form of this industry during the Crusades. In 1516, a family that grew wealthy through this industry built the world’s oldest still-used social housing complex in Augsburg. A “double-entry” method was used in this industry by the Bardi and Peruzzi families who dominated it in Italy prior to the Hundred Years’ War. During the Middle Ages, “Court Jews” largely controlled this industry due to the Church’s ban on usury. Both the Fuggers and the Rothschilds made their fortunes in this industry. For 10 points, name this industry that consists of the loaning and storing of money. ","answer":"ANSWER: banking [or word forms; accept investing; accept loaning money until read, but prompt after; prompt on business or financing or accounting] (The housing complex refers to the Fuggerei, and the “method” refers to double-entry bookkeeping.) <European History> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"2. Anne Geddes often photographs these subjects in bright and elaborate costumes. Norman Mailer claimed that giving one artist a camera was like giving a weapon to one of these people; that artist captured two identical examples of these people in black dresses with white collars and headbands for a photo imitated in Stanley Kubrick’s The Shining. Diane Arbus photographed one of these people in overalls with a strap fallen off as he holds a toy grenade in Central Park. The faces of two of these people are obscured in a photo of Florence Owens Thompson taken during the Great Depression. For 10 points, what type of people hug the title woman in Dorothea Lange’s Migrant Mother? ","answer":"ANSWER: children [or kids; accept babies or toddlers or youths or other such equivalents; accept boys or girls; prompt on brothers or sisters or siblings or twins] <Other Arts> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"3. Juliet Herbert, who taught English to this character’s creator, first translated the novel that is titled for this character. A declaration of love for this character is intercut with a farmer being awarded a prize in manure. A blind beggar sings under the window while this character dies, after which a Legion of Honor is given to a pharmacist. This character throws out a torn-up letter during a carriage ride with a man whom she meets while pretending to take piano lessons in Rouen (“roo-AWN”). This resident of Yonville (“yon-VEEL”) has affairs with Léon Dupuis (“duh-PWEE”) and Rodolphe Boulanger. For 10 points, name this character married to Charles, who kills herself with arsenic in a novel by Gustave Flaubert (“flo-BAIR”). ","answer":"ANSWER: Emma Bovary [or Madame Bovary; or Emma Rouault; prompt on Bovary or Rouault] <European Literature> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"4. Marvin Harris claimed that this thinker practiced “historical particularism” in opposition to contemporary theories of cultural evolution. The mnemonic “stones, tones, bones, and thrones” is used for a four-field classification that was long attributed to this thinker. At the Chicago World’s Fair, this scientist made a model village for fourteen Kwakiutl (“kwok-ee-OO-tull”) from British Columbia. After giving up “public anthropology,” he reproduced studies on the skull shapes of immigrants and their children in The Mind of Primitive Man, which promotes his idea of methodological cultural relativism. For 10 points, name this Columbia professor who taught Ruth Benedict and Margaret Mead in America’s first anthropology PhD program. ","answer":"ANSWER: Franz Boas <Social Science> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"5. Flynn’s taxonomy classifies the various designs and functionalities of these components, whose superscalar examples are classified as SISD (“sis-D”) or MIMD (“mim-D”). A paper titled First Draft of a Report on the EDVAC (“ED-vack”) marked the introduction of the von Neumann (“NOY-mahn”) model in designing these components. ALUs in these components can perform two’s complement, and signal buses transfer data between these components and peripherals. The clock rate of these components is typically measured in gigahertz. For 10 points, name these hardware components that carry out program instructions and are often referred to as the “brain” of a computer. ","answer":"ANSWER: CPUs [or central processing units; accept central processor; accept main processor; accept microprocessor; prompt on processors; prompt on processing units] <Other Science> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"6. In the aftermath of this campaign, a news anchor declared that he could not “have faith any longer in the silver linings” found “in the darkest clouds.” Soldiers about to initiate this campaign were told to “crack the sky, shake the earth” before attacking cities like Pleiku (“PLAY-koo”) and Cholon (“CHUH-lun”). An iconic photograph taken during this campaign shows a man in plaid being summarily shot in the head. Thousands of civilians were killed in massacres at Huế (“hway”) during this campaign, which also saw communist troops briefly seize the U.S. embassy in Saigon. For 10 points, name this 1968 offensive launched by North Vietnamese forces and named for a New Year’s holiday. ","answer":"ANSWER: Tet Offensive <American History> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"7. This artist riffed on earlier works in a painting that reduces a portrait of Madame Cézanne to a simple diagram as well as a depiction of his studio with Matisse’s The Dance in the background. This artist mocked abstract expressionism in paintings and sculptures of black-outlined brushstrokes. A painting by this artist shows a woman who would “rather sink than call Brad for help!” The title of one of this artist’s paintings appears in bold yellow text in front of an exploding fighter jet. This artist used speech bubbles and Ben-Day dots in many of his works, which were often inspired by comic books. For 10 points, name this Pop artist who painted Drowning Girl and Whaam! ","answer":"ANSWER: Roy Lichtenstein <Painting/Sculpture> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"8. In one myth, Nüwa cuts the legs off one of these animals named Ao to repair the sky. In the Iroquois creation myth, a frog spits onto the back of one of these animals so that Sky Woman has a place to stand. A common indigenous name for North America refers to the belief that the continent is held up by one of these animals. The earth is supported by elephants who all stand on the back of one of these animals, according to Hindu cosmology. After stealing Apollo’s cattle, Hermes uses an oxhide, a sheep’s guts, and a part from one of these animals to create a musical instrument. For 10 points, the lyre was made out of the shell of what type of animal? ","answer":"ANSWER: turtles [or tortoise] <Mythology> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"9. The appendix to a novel by this author categorizes a language into everyday phrases, compound words, and technical language, corresponding to A, B, and C vocabularies. This author produced a parodic translation of a phrase from Ecclesiastes (“uh-KLEE-zee-ASS-teez”) in an essay that attacks pretentious diction and dying metaphors as causing the decline of the English language. In a novel by this author, the lexicologist Syme becomes an “unperson” due to his intelligence. A fictional language created by this author introduced the terms “doublethink” and “thoughtcrime.” For 10 points, Newspeak restricts the thoughts of residents of Oceania in what author’s dystopian novel Nineteen Eighty-Four? ","answer":"ANSWER: George Orwell [or Eric Arthur Blair] (The lead-in describes “The Principles of Newspeak.”) <British Literature> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"0. A time-of-flight spectrometer named for this phenomenon uses an electrostatic field to focus ion beams. An ideal type of this phenomenon has intensity proportional to cosine theta and is named for Johann Heinrich Lambert. Ellipsometry uses measurements of this phenomenon to study thin films. This phenomenon does not occur for polarized light at Brewster’s angle. Davisson and Germer expected to see the diffuse form of this phenomenon in their namesake experiment, while in its specular form, the angle of incidence is equal to the outgoing angle. Optical fibers use the total internal form of, for 10 points, what phenomenon that occurs when light strikes a mirror? ","answer":"ANSWER: reflection [or word forms; accept total internal reflection; accept reflectron mass spectrometry] <Physics> Bonuses "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] Name this story in which two horses magically appear to the title character, whisking him away to his work and leaving a mysterious groom alone with his servant girl Rosa. ","answer":"ANSWER: “A Country Doctor” [or “Ein Landarzt”] [10] “A Country Doctor” was written by this author. Gregor Samsa wastes away after he is transformed into a giant insect overnight in this man’s novella The Metamorphosis. "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] Description acceptable. This character from The Metamorphosis delivers food to Gregor and is the only one who will go in his room alone. The story ends with her stretching her legs while on the tram. ","answer":"ANSWER: Gregor’s sister [or Grete Samsa] <European Literature> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] This computer scientist popularized structured programming, which focuses on writing clear, readable code. He also devised an algorithm that solves the shortest path problem in a graph with non-negative edge weights. ","answer":"ANSWER: Edsger W. Dijkstra (“DIKE-struh”) "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] Languages such as C++ (“C-plus-plus”) and Java exemplify this widely used programming paradigm, which allows for the creation of variables, data structures, and classes that contain data in the form of fields. ","answer":"ANSWER: object-oriented programming [prompt on OOP] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] In this programming paradigm, the output of a procedure is solely dependent on its arguments. Examples of languages that support this paradigm include Common Lisp and OCaml (“oh-camel”). ","answer":"ANSWER: functional programming [prompt on declarative programming] <Other Science> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] Name this African-American thinker who collected his essays on race in The Souls of Black Folk. He came to oppose Booker T. Washington’s Atlanta Compromise and advocated for civil rights advances in the early 1900s. ","answer":"ANSWER: W. E. B. Du Bois (“doo boyce”) [or William Edward Burghardt Du Bois] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] To oppose Washington’s accommodation of white rule, Du Bois founded this short-lived civil rights organization named for the “mighty current” of change it hoped to inspire. It was later absorbed by the NAACP (“N-double-A-C-P”). ","answer":"ANSWER: Niagara Movement "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] In a 1935 book on this period, Du Bois challenged the racialized “Dunning School” perspective and defended African-Americans’ role in it. Eric Foner has extensively cited Du Bois in his studies of this period. ","answer":"ANSWER: Reconstruction [accept Black Reconstruction in America] <American History> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] Name this choreographer known for his 1960 production of La fille mal gardée (“la FEE mall gar-DAY”). This longtime chief choreographer for Ninette de Valois included his “Fred step” in many productions. ","answer":"ANSWER: Frederick Ashton [or Sir Frederick William Mallandaine Ashton] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] Ashton’s first major ballet was a comic version of this Prokofiev ballet based on a fairy tale. The fairy godmother sends the title character to a secret garden with her prince at its end. ","answer":"ANSWER: Cinderella [accept Zolushka; accept Cendrillon] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] After de Valois left, Ashton became the director of this ballet company based in Covent (“CUV-int”) Garden. It got its current name after it received a charter from the Queen. ","answer":"ANSWER: The Royal Ballet [accept Vic-Wells Ballet; accept Sadler’s Wells Ballet] <Other Arts> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] Name these sets of behaviors attached to certain jobs, genders, and other situations. People may emulate “model” persons named for them when “playing” make-believe games such as House or RPGs. ","answer":"ANSWER: social roles [accept role congruity theory; accept role models; accept role-playing games; accept role theory] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] Role theory adopts the idea of people as “actors” from this symbolic interactionist’s dramaturgical model. This sociologist wrote on that subject in The Presentation of Self in Everyday Life. ","answer":"ANSWER: Erving Goffman "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] Labelling theory asserts that criminals fall into the role of a criminal because they believe that they are a “criminal.” In this situation with a three-word name, a person’s belief that X will happen causes X to happen. ","answer":"ANSWER: self-fulfilling prophecy (also coined by Merton) <Social Science> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] Name these Roman priestesses who served 30-year terms maintaining the city’s sacred fire. ","answer":"ANSWER: Vestal Virgins [or Vestals or Vestalis; prompt on Virgins] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] Upper class Roman women were the only lawful participants in an annual festival honoring this goddess. During that festival to this goddess in 62 BC, Publius Clodius Pulcher dressed as a woman and tried to seduce Julius Caesar’s wife, leading Caesar to divorce her. ","answer":"ANSWER: Bona Dea [accept Bona Dea scandal] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] Women were also essential in spreading this religion across the Roman empire. St. Helena encouraged her son Constantine the Great to promote toleration of this religion. ","answer":"ANSWER: Christianity <European History> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] Name this Restoration playwright and novelist. A group of soldiers court, threaten, and are threatened by local women in her play The Rover. ","answer":"ANSWER: Aphra Behn (“bane”) "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] Behn turned to writing after a stint in debtor’s prison because she wasn’t paid for her work in this profession for Charles II. George Smiley and Alec Leamas are members of this profession created by John Le Carré. ","answer":"ANSWER: spy [accept secret agent] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] In Behn’s novel Oroonoko, the title prince is captured by English slavers and brought to this continent, where he starts a rebellion. Candide travels to this continent to search for El Dorado. ","answer":"ANSWER: South America [prompt on America] <British Literature> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] This legendary phantom ship, the subject of an opera by Richard Wagner, is said to forever sail the seas. It is named for its European country of origin. ","answer":"ANSWER: The Flying Dutchman [or De Vliegende Hollander; or Der fliegende Holländer] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] In 2018, a record number of real-life “ghost ships” full of dead sailors from this country washed up on other shores. This country claims to have found the cave where the mythical founder Dangun (“DAHN-goon”) lived. ","answer":"ANSWER: North Korea [or Democratic People’s Republic of Korea; prompt on Korea; do not accept or prompt on “South Korea” or “Republic of Korea”] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] During Ragnarok, Loki is said to ride on Naglfar (“naggle-far”), a ship constructed from these objects taken from the corpses of the dead. ","answer":"ANSWER: nails [accept toenails or fingernails] <Mythology> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] Name this phenomenon that, according to the EPR paradox, violates locality. ","answer":"ANSWER: quantum entanglement "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] Measuring a property of one particle causes this event to occur to the entire entangled system. This irreversible event occurs when a wavefunction in superposition is projected onto an eigenstate by observation. ","answer":"ANSWER: wavefunction collapse "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] Quantum entanglement has been proposed as a source of the “arrow of” this concept, which states that this concept is asymmetric. This quantity is measured in seconds. ","answer":"ANSWER: time <Physics> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] Name this Spanish city. The Disrobing of Christ hangs in this city’s cathedral, and a painting titled View of this city features a dramatic, cloudy sky. ","answer":"ANSWER: Toledo [accept View of Toledo] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] This Mannerist artist painted View of Toledo. His painting The Opening of the Fifth Seal depicts a scene from the Book of Revelation and was an inspiration for Picasso’s Les Demoiselles D’Avignon (“lay duh-mwah-ZELL dah-veen-YON”). ","answer":"ANSWER: El Greco [or Doménikos Theotokópoulos] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] In this El Greco painting, Jesus, Mary, and many saints welcome the title figure to heaven while St. Stephen and St. Augustine lower his body into the ground. This painting is split between an earthly lower half and a heavenly upper half. ","answer":"ANSWER: The Burial of the Count of Orgaz [accept answers referring to the burial or funeral of the Count of Orgaz] <Painting/Sculpture> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] Name this American poet. The speaker searches for “the drowned face / always staring toward the sun” and “the ribs of the disaster” in the title poem of this author’s collection Diving into the Wreck. ","answer":"ANSWER: Adrienne Rich [or Adrienne Cecile Rich] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] The speaker “wander’d off” and “look’d up in perfect silence at the stars” in this author’s poem “When I Heard the Learn’d Astronomer.” This poet also wrote Leaves of Grass. ","answer":"ANSWER: Walt Whitman "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] The speaker of Rich’s poem “Yom Kippur 1984” searches for “something to bind me to this coast as” this Whitman poem “once bound me back there.” This poem notes, “the great star early droop’d in the western sky.” ","answer":"ANSWER: “When Lilacs Last in the Dooryard Bloom’d” [prompt on “lilacs in the dooryard”] <American Literature> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] Name this task that Edmund Halley failed to perform by studying isogonic lines of magnetism. John Harrison invented a series of devices dubbed H1 through H5 to do this task, but he was swindled out of the prize money. ","answer":"ANSWER: calculating longitude [accept the longitude problem; prompt on answers regarding accurate timekeeping; do not accept or prompt on anything about “latitude”] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] Following World War I, four of Harrison’s marine chronometers were rediscovered in this specific location’s Royal Observatory. This London area with a namesake “Mean Time” sits directly on the Prime Meridian. ","answer":"ANSWER: Greenwich (“GREN-itch”) [accept Royal Observatory, Greenwich; accept Greenwich Mean Time] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] This other Londoner tried to solve the longitude problem, but largely quit after developing a spring-powered pocket watch. This member of the Royal Society coined the word “cell” in his best-seller, Micrographia. ","answer":"ANSWER: Robert Hooke <European History> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] Name this educational treatise which proposed that women like Sophie should only be educated for the pleasure of men. Jean-Jacques Rousseau considered it his most important work. ","answer":"ANSWER: Émile "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] This philosopher was prompted in part by the sexist views on women’s education presented in Émile to write A Vindication of the Rights of Women. ","answer":"ANSWER: Mary Wollstonecraft "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] Rousseau’s belief that women soften men and deprive them of the masculinity of the ancients in part motivated a letter critiquing this other thinker’s proposition to establish a theater in Geneva. After that letter, this physicist resigned from co-editing the Encyclopédie with Denis Diderot. ","answer":"ANSWER: Jean-Baptiste le Rond d’Alembert (“dal-om-BAIR”) <Philosophy> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] Name this condition required for anammox (“ann-AMM-ox”) to occur. “Facultative” organisms switch to fermentation under this condition. ","answer":"ANSWER: anaerobic [accept lack of oxygen or similar phrases; accept obligate anaerobes or facultative anaerobes] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] When food is fermented in an environment lacking sufficient salinity or acidity, there is a chance that a species in this genus of bacteria will grow. That species in this genus causes botulism. ","answer":"ANSWER: Clostridium "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] According to some chefs, it is best to use water with this quality when fermenting cucumbers to make pickles. This term refers to a low concentration of calcium and magnesium ions. ","answer":"ANSWER: soft water <Biology> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] Name this Mesoamerican civilization whose decline in the 8th and 9th centuries led to the effective abandonment of cities like Tikal in the Yucatan peninsula. ","answer":"ANSWER: Mayan civilization "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] Early classical Mayan cities traded and fought with this powerful city-state in the Valley of Mexico. It is home to the Avenue of the Dead and the Pyramids of the Sun and the Moon. ","answer":"ANSWER: Teotihuacan (“TAY-oh-tee-wah-KAHN”) "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] This Mexican state contains Tulum, a walled port city built centuries after most Mayan cities collapsed. This state became a Mexican territory in 1902 after its indigenous Mayan population was defeated in the Caste War. ","answer":"ANSWER: Quintana Roo (“roh”) <World History> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] Name this fairy tale character who “took an axe to the wolf” and “saw the glistening, virgin white of my grandmother’s bones” in that poem. She is named for an accessory with a certain color. ","answer":"ANSWER: Little Red Riding Hood [or Little Red Cap] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] In this author’s retelling, Little Red Riding Hood sleeps with the wolf instead. This author of Nights at the Circus included many fairy tale retellings in The Bloody Chamber. ","answer":"ANSWER: Angela Olive Carter [or Angela Pearce; or Angela Stalker] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] Outfits featuring red cloaks in this novel allude to Little Red Riding Hood. In this novel, Nick and the Commander are thought to be stand-ins for the huntsman and the wolf. ","answer":"ANSWER: The Handmaid’s Tale <World/Other Literature> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] Name this alloy produced with the Bessemer process. Chromium may be added to this alloy to increase corrosion resistance. ","answer":"ANSWER: steel "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] Pearlite consists of layered ferrite and this orthorhombic compound whose formula is Fe3C. It is also known as iron carbide. ","answer":"ANSWER: cementite "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] Pearlite consists of alternating layers of two of these states, whose namesake diagrams plot temperature against pressure or weight percent. For water, these states include solid, liquid, and gas. ","answer":"ANSWER: phases [or phase diagram; prompt on state of matter] <Chemistry> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] Name this Italian “father of the piano” who created six sonatinas for the instrument. Like his student Carl Czerny (“CHAIR-nee”), he wrote an etude collection titled Gradus ad parnassum. ","answer":"ANSWER: Muzio Clementi "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] Clementi is regarded as the founder of a piano-playing school based in this city. Johann Christian Bach is often nicknamed for this city, which also names a set of twelve Haydn symphonies including “Surprise,” “Military,” and “Drumroll.” ","answer":"ANSWER: London [accept London Pianoforte School; accept London Bach; accept London symphonies] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] Clementi’s students included John Field, the Irish inventor of this genre of character pieces. Clementi-admirer Frédéric Chopin wrote 21 of these pieces, which are named for evoking the night. ","answer":"ANSWER: nocturnes [or notturno] <Classical Music> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] The industry experienced the largest percent crash since the dotcom bubble after this country threatened to ban the firm Ethereum. The American-owned GM Daewoo competes with Hyundai and Kia in this country’s automobile economy. ","answer":"ANSWER: South Korea [or the Republic of Korea; accept Hanguk or Namhan; prompt on Korea; do not accept or prompt on “Democratic People’s Republic of Korea” or “DPRK” or “North Korea”] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] In 2018, this leader announced Petro, a cryptocurrency backed by oil fields in the Atapirire (“AH-tah-pee-REE-ray”) Parish, as part of an “economic offensive.” This leader’s namesake “diet” refers to how his citizens lost an average of 26 pounds in 2016 due to food shortages. ","answer":"ANSWER: Nicolás Maduro Moros "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] In 2018, David A. Marcus spearheaded development of this cryptocurrency produced by Facebook and geared towards “financial inclusion.” Nydia Velázquez and other House Democrats have argued that this cryptocurrency would “break the international monetary system.” ","answer":"ANSWER: Libra <CE/Geo/Other/Pop Culture> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] Name this deity, whose victory over a buffalo demon is celebrated during Navaratri. During Ashwin, frenzied drummers known as dhaki perform as part of a similar, overlapping holiday, this deity’s namesake “puja.” ","answer":"ANSWER: Durgā [accept Durga Puja; accept Navadurgā; accept Durgotsava; prompt on Devi; prompt on Parvati; prompt on Adi Parashakti; prompt on Gauri] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] During Navaratri, local artisans produce festive displays full of golu, a type of these objects. In reality, Haiti has nothing to do with the “Voodoo” variety of these things, which can be stuck with pins to harm one’s enemies. ","answer":"ANSWER: dolls [accept Voodoo dolls; accept figurines; prompt on poppets; prompt on effigies; prompt on idols; prompt on models] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] Two weeks following Durga Puja is this other Hindu festival. During this five-day festival, individuals create vibrant rangoli floor art, and light many oil lamps known as diyas. ","answer":"ANSWER: Diwali [accept Divali, Deepawali, or Dipavali; prompt on Dhanteras; prompt on Festival of Lights] <Religion>"}]
